

### **PROFILE**

A simple IT graduate with more than two years of experience in creating web applications. I am very passionate in learning new things that will make me competent. I am a good listener and able to grasp new concepts quickly and efficiently.

#### **EDUCATION**

# BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY (LADDERIZED COURSE)

TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY OF THE PHILIPPINES – TAGUIG (2016-2017)

# COMPUTER ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY (TECHNICIAN COURSE)

TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY OF THE PHILIPPINES – TAGUIG (2012-2015)

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

Age: 23 yrs. old
Date of Birth: August 06, 1996
Place of Birth: Makati City
Civil Status: Single
Nationality: Filipino
Height: 5'6"

Religion: Roman Catholic

#### CONTACT

#### ADDRESS:

Blk 18 Lot 2 11-k 11<sup>th</sup> Ave. HHSG North Signal Village Taguig City.

## CELLPHONE:

0927-0752905

#### **SAMPLE PROJECTS:**

https://asraquem00110.github.io/portfolio/

#### GITHUB:

https://github.com/asraquem00110

#### LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/alvin-raquem-167799146

#### **EMAIL:**

raquem.alvin@gmail.com

# **ALVIN S. RAQUEM**

## WFB DFVFI OPFR

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Web and Application Developer**

E-CTK Solutions Inc. (ESI) / Armored Transport Plus, Inc. (ATPI) No. 2 Avis Street, Bagong Ilog, Pasig City Philippines. August 14, 2017 – Present.

- \* In-house developer.
- \* Automate the manual process of company's operations.
- \* Enhance and modify existing system.
- \* Analyze program/system based on the required functionalities.
- \* Generate needed/requested reports.
- \* Documentation of program/system.

#### Internship (Technical Support)

Nexus Technologies Inc.

G/F Don Pablo building, 114 Amorsolo Street, Legazpi Village, Makati City.

October 2014 - March 2015.

#### **SKILLS**

#### **PROGRAMMING**

BACKEND TECHNOLOGY PHP LARAVEL NODEJS

MYSQL

FRONTEND TECHNOLOGY HTML,CSS & BOOTSTRAP

JAVASCRIPT JQUERY AJAX REST

**VUEJS** 

## MOBILE DEV TECHNOLOGY

ANDROID (JAVA) - BASIC KNOWLEDGE

IONIC + VUEJS CAPACITOR

#### OTHERS

Familiar with OOP approach and MVC pattern.

Knowledge in Microsoft Windows operating system.

Knowledge in Microsoft Office Applications: MS Word, MS PowerPoint, MS Excel.

Experience in Linux server.

Knowledge in Computer Software, and Hardware Installation.

### TRAININGS AND SEMINARS ATTENDED

# Computer Week Seminar 2014

"Enhancing Character for Technology Advancement" TUP-Taguig May 19 – 22, 2014

Secure IT 2019

"A Data Privacy and Business Continuity Forum" Dusit Thani Manila Hotel, Makati City July 25, 2019

#### **CHARACTER REFERENCE**

Mr. Wendel Capangada Associate Business Intelligence and Automation Lazada 09178544313 Mr. Romel Neri Science Research Specialist DOST-TAPI 09291290645 Mr. Olegario Barcelon Jr Lead Software Developer ATPI 09159106599

# PROJECT / TASK ACCOMPLISHED

# **CIT MONITORING SYSTEM** > A web system for Cash in Transit department to monitor the status of their trip. Modify and enhance the existing mobile app that is being -2017 used by the teller to update the status of their dispatch order. Technology used in web application are PHP, MYSQL, HTML & CSS, BOOTSTRAP, JAVASCRIPT/JQUERY, and AJAX. > Technology used for mobile app are JAVA (Android Studio IDE), REST protocol, and GOOGLE MAP API. PERSONNEL PROFILING Modify the existing system that tracks/records the information's of **SYSTEM - 2018** security personnel. Technology used are PHP, MySQL, HTML & CSS, BOOTSTRAP, JAVACRIPT/JQUERY and AJAX. **EMS (EVENT MANAGEMENT** Modify and add some report generation module for existing **SYSTEM) - 2018** ticketing system. Enhance dashboard display. > Technology used are PHP, MYSQL, HTML & CSS, BOOTSTRAP, JAVASCRIPT/JQUERY and AJAX. **BIOMETRICS TIME IN/OUT** > Application using Digital Persona 4500 biometric device that tracks TRACKER - 2018 the time in and out for selected departments. > Technology used are VB.NET, MYSQL & Digital Persona sdk. **ECCAMSTAT PORTAL** > A web portal for Retail Cash Deposit Machine (RCD) that display or generate required reports for each requirements of different clients -2019 (Banks). Created a PHP Script that is called in a Cron Job in Linux to automate the sending of crediting files in SFTP Server of Client. > Technology used are PHP, MYSQL, HTML & CSS, BOOTSTRAP, JAVASCRIPT/JQUERY and AJAX.